A Guide to the Virginia Marine Resources Commission Oyster Chart Collection, 1894-1977
Library of Virginia
- J.K. Sinclair. Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Severn River, Northwest Branch and Vaughn's Creek Gloucester County, Virginia. Scale 1:5000. 32 x45 inches. Map on drafting paper. (W 76°26'35"/N 37°18'36"; W 76°29'18"/N 37°18'36"; W 76°29'17"/N 37°20'22"; W 76°26'34"/N 37°20'22"; W 76°26'35"/N 37°18'36"),1974. (Box 6)
- J.K. Sinclair. Map of Oyster Planting Grounds in Severn River Southwest Branch. Scale 1:5,000. 32 x 57 inches. Manuscript map on drafting paper. (W 76°26'45"/N 37°17'19"; W 76°27'42"/N 37°17'51"; W 76°26'00"/N 37°19'47"; W 76°25'03"/N 37°19'15"; W 76°26'45"/N 37°17'19"),1974. (Box 6)
- C.T. Hudgins. Map of Oyster Planting Ground Horn Harbor Mathews Virginia by C.T. Hudgins. Scale 1:5,000. 29 x 42 inches. (76°16'08"/N 37°20'48"; W 76°18'27"/N 37°21'30"; W 76°18'00"/N 37°22'27"; W 76°15'41"/N 37°21'45"; W 76°16'08"/N 37°20'48"),Not dated. (Box 7)
- C.T. Hudgins. Map of Oyster Planting Ground Horn Harbor Mathews Virginia by C.T. Hudgins. Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 43 inches. (W 76°16'08"/N 37°20'48"; W 76°18'27"/N 37°21'30"; W 76°18'00"/N 37°22'27"; W 76°15'41"/N 37°21'45"; W 76°16'08"/N 37°20'48"),Not dated. (Box 7)
- James Baylor. Mobjack Bay Public Oyster Ground State of Virginia 1894. Scale 1:20,000. 30.5 x 41.75 inches.(W 76°21'20"/N 37°15'33"; W 76°25'57"/N 37°19'50"; W 76°21'25"/N 37°22'56"; W 76°16'48"/N 37°18'39"; W 76°21'20"/N 37°15'33"),1894. (Box 7)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Mobjack Bay, Virginia. Scale 1:6,000. 20 x 30 inches.(W 76°21'33"/N 37°17'30"; W 76°24'56"/N 37°20'44"; W 76°21'54"/N 37°22'45"; W 76°18'31"/N 37°19'31"; W 76°21'33"/N 37°17'30"),1924. (Box 7)
- Fred E.Ruediger.Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds North River Gloucester and Mathews Counties Virginia 1936 Commission of Fisheries.Scale 1:10,000 32.25 x 53.5 inches.(W 76°27'39"--W 76°21'45"/N 37°27'02"--N 37°21'28"),1936. (Box 7)
- Fred E. Ruediger.Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds East River Mathews County,Virginia.Scale 1:10,000.31.25 x 55 inches.(W 76°22'00"--W 76°19'29"/N 37°25'01"--N 37°21'38"),1936. (Box 7)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Horn Harbor Mathews County Virginia 1939.Scale 1:5,000.31 x 53 inches.(W 76°16'08"/N 37°20'46"; W 76°18'48"/N 37°21'34"; W 76°18'14"/N 37°22'45"; W 76°15'34"/N 37°21'57"; W 76°16'08"/N 37°20'46"),1939. (Box 7)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Horn Harbor Mathews County Virginia.Scale 1:5,000. 31 x 55 inches.(W 76°15'51"/N 37°20'18"; W 76°19'31"/N 37°21'14"; W 76°19'01"/N 37°22'35"; W 76°15'16"/N 37°22'04"; W 76°15'51"/N 37°20'18"),1939. (Box 7)
- J.K. Sinclair. Oyster Planting Grounds in East River Mathews County, Virginia, Commonwealth of Virginia, Marine Resources Commission, Revised January 1970. Scale 1:10,000. 30 x 53 inches.(W 76°21'17"/N 37°21'40"; W 76°22'14"/N 37°26'36"; W 76°20'28"/N 37°26'49"; W 76°19'31"/N 37°21'53"; W 76°21'17"/N 37°21'40"),1970. (Box 7)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Accomac County, Virginia 1935. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 55 inches. (W 75°26'18"--W 75°18'47"/N 38°00'50"--N 37°56'38"),1935. (Box 8)
- Pocomoke and Tangier Sound. Scale 1:40,000.(W 75°55'20"--W 75°51'53"/N 37°58'46"--N 37°57'07"),No date. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 1 Sand Bar-Shad Landing Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 54 inches.(W 75°42'39"/N 37°52'01"; W 75°47'10"/N 37°55'23"; W 75°40'42"/N 38°00'46"; W 75°36'11"/N 37°57'24"; W 75°42'39"/N 37°52'01"),1936. (Box 8)
- Fred. E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 2 Messongo Resurvey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. Scale 1:10,000. (W 75°45'23"--W 75°38'55"/N 37°54'43"--N 37°53'11"),1936. (Box 8)
- A copy of J.B. Gibbs map; copied by G. H. Badger. C.S. Map Showing Property Line, Oyster Ground, Etc. At or Near Nandua Wharf, Accomack County, Virginia. Surveyed June 7, 1946. Scale 1:1200. 16.25 x 20.5 inches. (W 75°50'59"--W 75°50'59"/N 37°37'27"--N 37°37'27"),1946. (Box 8)
- J.B. Gibb, C.S. & Assisted by G.H. Badger, County Surveyor of Northampton Co., Va. No. 233 Stingray Point Cove Accomack County, Virginia. Scale 1:5.00. 18.75 x 39.75 inches. (W 75°40'24"/N 37°28'49"; W 75°41'25"/N 37°29'21"; W 75°41'01"/N 37°29'43"; W 75°40'52"/N 37°30'05"; W 75°40'44"/N 37°30'11"; W 75°39'34"/N 37°29'49"; W 75°40'24"/N 37°28'49"),1932. (Box 8)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr. Additional Public Ground Pocomoke Sound Northwest Side Saxis Island Accomack County, Virginia. Scale 1:10,000. 13.5 x 27.5 inches. (W 75°44'20"/N 37°53'56"; W 75°45'24"/N 37°54'08"; W 75°42'48"/N 37°56'25"; W 75°44'20"/N 37°53'56"),1955. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Accomac County Virginia 1933. Scale in feet; 1:10,000. 31.25 x 55 inches.(W 75°22'22"/N 37°56'09"; W 75°27'26"/N 37°56'22"; W 75°22'44"/N 38°00'50"; W 75°15'15"/N 38°01'33"; W 75°22'22"/N 37°56'09"),1933. (Box 8)
- Geo. H. Badger, Jr. Pocomoke Sound Sand Bar - Shell Landing Accomack County Virginia. Scale 1:10,000. 35.5 x 63 inches. (W 75°45'35"--W 75°37'32"/N 37°58'41"--N 37°55'23"),1964. (Box 8)
- Pocomoke Sound Chart No Public Oyster Grounds in Pungoteague Creek Virginia. Scale 1:12,000. 18.5 x 19.5 inches.(W 75°51'09"/N 37°39'54"; W 75°52'01"/N 37°40'10"; W 75°52'16"/N 37°40'00"; W 75°52'35"/N 37°40'09"; W 75°51'15"/N 37°40'50"; W 75°51'09"/N 37°40'35"; W 75°50'29"/N 37°40'33"; W 75°50'07"/N 37°40'25"; W 75°49'56"/N 37°40'32"; W 75°49'50"/N 37°40'28"; W 75°50'13"/N 37°40'09"; W 75°50'43"/N 37°40'15"; W 75°51'09"/N 37°39'54"),No date. (Box 8)
- Pocomoke Sound Chart No Public Oyster Grouns in Pungoteague Creek Virginia. No Date. Scale 1:12,000. 18.5 x 19.5 inches. (W 75°51'09"/N 37°39'54"; W 75°52'01"/N 37°40'10"; W 75°52'16"/N 37°40'00"; W 75°52'35"/N 37°40'09"; W 75°51'15"/N 37°40'50"; W 75°51'09"/N 37°40'35"; W 75°50'29"/N 37°40'33"; W 75°50'07"/N 37°40'25"; W 75°49'56"/N 37°40'32"; W 75°49'50"/N 37°40'28"; W 75°50'13"/N 37°40'09"; W 75°50'43"/N 37°40'15"; W 75°51'09"/N 37°39'54"),No date. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 1 Sand Bar-Shad Landing Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 54.25 inches. (W 75°58'10"--W 75°44'55"/N 37°53'51"--N 37°48'09"),1936. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 1 Sand Bar-Shad Landing Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. 1936. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 54.25 inches. (W 75°58'10"--W 75°44'55"/N 37°53'51"--N 37°48'09"),1936. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 1 Sand Bar-Shad Landing Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. Scale 1:10,000. 31 x 54.25 inches. (W 75°58'10"--W 75°44'55"/N 37°53'51"--N 37°48'09"),1936. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Burtons, Bradfords and Swash Bays. Scale 1:10,000. 31.5 x 58.5 inches. (W 75°38'24"/N 37°30'37"; W 75°43'39"/N 37°33'10"; W 75°38'41"/N 37°39'38"; W 75°33'26"/N 37°37'05"; W 75°38'24"/N 37°30'37"),1935. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 2 Messongo Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. Scale 1:10,000. 32 x 55 inches. (W 75°48'13"--W 75°36'05"/N 37°56'27"--N 37°51'30"),1936. (Box 8)
- Fred E. Ruediger. Sheet No. 2 Messongo Re-Survey of Oyster Planting Grounds Pocomoke Sound Accomac County Virginia 1936. Scale 1:10,000. 32 x 55 inches. (W 75°48'13"--W 75°36'05"/N 37°56'27"--N 37°51'30"),1936. (Box 8)
- C.C. Yates. Charts of Maryland Oyster survey 1906-1912. 42 charts. 32 x 41 inches.,1913.
- 1924 Washington, D.C. District Fish Stake Charts for commission of Fisheries Virginia. Entire folio 24 x 20 inches, entire folio ,1924.